Selim Maurice Franklin papers, 1873-1931
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Selim Maurice Franklin papers, 1873-1931
AZ 336
Franklin, Selim Maurice, 1859-1931
38 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Selim Maurice Franklin was an attorney in Tucson, Arizona. He represented numerous mining interests and property holder in southern Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series:
Series I: Personal and Family Papers, 1881-1927
Series II: Professional Papers, 1873-1931
Series III: Merrill P. Freeman Papers, 1878-1927
Series IV: Zeckendorf Family Papers, 1887-1911
Series V: William Herring Papers, 1882-1911
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of legal papers and financial records relating to mining companies, cattle companies, land grants, railroads, public utilities, banks, bankruptcies, estates, and property, mostly in Arizona. Similar material is also present from Franklin's father-in-law,William Herring, also an attorney. A smaller amount of material is present from Merrill P. Freeman, Tucson Postmaster and an associate with Franklin in various enterprises. Among the many groups represented are the Copper Queen Consolidated Mining Co., Detroit Copper Mining Co., Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines Ltd., Mammoth Cyanide Co., Seventy-nine Mining Co., South San Xavier Copper Co., San Rafael Cattle Co., "Y" Cattle Co., El Paso and Southwestern Railroad Co., and the Zeckendorf family.
An index to the hundreds of personal and corporate names, and also subjects, is present in the inventory. Franklin's family correspondence includes material from his uncle Lionel Mark Jacobs, a Tucson banker, whose estate papers are also present. Franklin's professional correspondence details activities in business investments, politics, the Arizona State Bar, and the University of Arizona. Major correspondents are Albert Steinfeld and H. W. Blaisdell.
Franklin, Selim Maurice, 1859-1928 -- Archives; Herring, William, 1833-1912 -- Archives; Jacobs, Lionel, 1841-1922; Freeman, M. P. (Merrill P.), b. 1844; Steinfeld, Albert, 1854-1935 -- Correspondence; Blaisdell, H. W. -- Correspondence; Zeckendorf family; Copper Queen Consolidated Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; Detroit Copper Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd. -- Records and correspondence; Seventy-nine Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; Mammoth Cyanide Company -- Records and correspondence; South San Xavier Copper Company -- Records and correspondence; San Rafael Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; "Y" Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; El Paso and Southwestern Railroad Company -- Records and correspondence; Lawyers -- Arizona; Land grants -- Arizona; Banks and banking -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence; Public utilities -- Arizona; Real property -- Arizona; Canals -- Arizona; Mining corporations -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence; Cattle trade -- Arizona; Jews -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Arizona -- History -- To 1912 -- Sources; Arizona -- History -- 1912-1950 -- Sources; Arizona -- Politics and government -- To 1950; Correspondence; Letter books; Speeches
Container List
- Series I: Personal and Family Papers, 1881-1927
  - Correspondence: A. M. "Abe" Franklin (brother). 1887-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence: Bertha Herring (sister-in-law). 1909-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: C. W. Clum (brother-in-law) and Mary G. Clum (sister-in-law). 1905-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Thomas R. Sorin (brother-in-law). 1898, 1916-1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Albert E. Jacobs (uncle). 1887-1898 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Belle Jacobs (aunt). 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Barron M. Jacobs (uncle) and family. 1894-1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Jacobs Family. 1888-1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Calisher Family. 1889-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous Family. 1888-1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Bureau of University Travel (daughter's trip abroad). 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Selim M. Franklin (nephew). 1887-1922 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: A. M. "Abe" Franklin (nephew). 1920-1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Miscellaneous personal and business. 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs financial notes (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
    "Inventories" of accounts, stock records, contributions, property and assessments, dividends and interest, etc.
  - Lionel M. Jacobs bills: Clothing. 1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs bills: Clubs, Medical. 1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs bills: Various. 1921 (Box 2)
    Includes bills for food, hotels, house and property repairs, plants, stationery, etc.
  - Lionel M. Jacobs contributions to charity (chiefly to post-war Jewish relief organizations). 1919-1922 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs property in Arizona, California and Missouri. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Loupe vs. Jacobs and Jacobs vs. Hawley. 1886-1894 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Jacobs et al vs. Jarrett, Gardner et al. 1888 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Jacobs vs. Washburn. 1889-1890 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Jacobs vs. Childs. 1894 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Jacobs et al vs. City of Tucson. 1906 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Harvey & Goodfellow vs. Jacobs (estate of Dr. George Goodfellow). 1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs legal cases: Jacobs vs. Gertrude Cohn et al. 1914 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs federal income taxes. 1915, 1918-1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Anglo and London Paris National Bank. 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Arizona National Bank, Tucson, Arizona. 1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Border National Bank, El Paso, Texas. 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: City National Bank, El Paso, Texas. 1920-1922 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: First National Bank, El Paso, Texas. 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: National Bank of Arizona, Phoenix, Arizona. 1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: First Mortgage Company of El Paso. 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Miscellaneous mortgage and brokerage firms. 1915-1922 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: Franklin and Heighton statements. 1911-1921 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: general. 1922-1927 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs will and legal papers. 1922-1925? (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: mortgage companies. 1922-1926 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs Correspondence: banks. 1924-1927 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs bank statements.: Arizona National Bank, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs checks.: Arizona National Bank, Tucson, Arizona (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lionel M. Jacobs miscellaneous financial records including bills, receipts, reports on rental collections, etc. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Blaisdell, H. W. 1886-1913 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence: Smith, W. C. 1881-1902 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence: Donau, Hugo T. 1897-1918 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Steinfeld, Albert. 1892-1925 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence regarding the estate of Isaac Williams and "the Bell matter."
  - Correspondence: Farley, Hugh. 1887-1916 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Fenner, Dr. H. W. 1893-1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Oatman, C. H. 1888-1918 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Shinn, J. C. and Family. 1890-1926 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: University of Arizona. 1888-1927 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    Includes letters from the Board of Regents, various governors, presidents, professors and state officials.
  - Correspondence: Blake, W. P. of the University of Arizona. 1896-1899 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Forbes, Robert H. of the University of Arizona. 1899-1919 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: University of California. 1887-1927 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Includes letters from classmates, alumni organization, etc.
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous personal. 1887-1927 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Contributions. 1894-1925 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Life Insurance. 1891-1926 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Membership: Tucson Lodge No. 4, F. & A. M. 1894-1895 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Tucson Lodge No. 385, Order of Elks. 1898-1912 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Old Pueblo Club. 1911-1924 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: American Mining Congress, Arizona Chapter. 1916 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Tucson Golf and Country Club. 1905-1926 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: American Association for Advancement of Science. 1920 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Arizona Archaeological & Historical Society. 1924 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Arizona Industrial Congress. 1924 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: (Tucson) Literary Club. No date (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Tucson Chautauqua Association. No date (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Transportation and Travel. 1889-1927 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Political correspondence: Ashurst, Henry F. 1916-1918 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Ellinwood, E. E. 1896-1903 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Goldwater, Morris. 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Hughes, L. C. 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Murphy, N. O. 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Smith, Mark. 1888-1919 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Political correspondence: Zulick, C. M. 1893-1894 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Oil. 1901-1925 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Railroad correspondence: Arizona Narrow Gauge Railroad Company. 1890-1891 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Railroad correspondence: El Paso & Northeastern Railroad Company. 1899 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Railroad correspondence: Railway Holding Company, Tucson, Arizona. 1911-1912 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Railroad correspondence: El Paso & Southwestern Railroad. 1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: "Wham Robbery" Case. 1889-1890 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Capital Commission, Phoenix site. 1889 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Arizona Corporation Commission. 1912-1919 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: World War I. Includes letters regarding Pima Council of Defense, U. S. Food Administration Pledge Card Campaign, Red Cross, Liberty Loan drives, etc. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Chamber of Commerce, Tucson, Arizona. 1903-1925 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: U. S. Department of the Interior Land Office. 1887-1919 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: District Attorney, Pinal County, Arizona. 1891-1903 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Recorder, Pinal County, Arizona. 1889-1902 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Sheriff, Pinal County, Arizona. 1891-1902 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Arizona Supreme Court. 1894-1911, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: U. S. District Courts. 1887-1912 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Series II: Professional Papers, 1873-1927
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material, 1884-1928
    - Professional correspondence: Cooper, William F. 1898-1903 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Professional correspondence: Davis, H. C. 1893-1898 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Professional correspondence: Goodrich, Ben. 1901-1912 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Professional correspondence: Gregg, F. W. 1887-1902 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Professional correspondence: Jeffords, H. R. and family. 1888-1901 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Professional correspondence: Jones, Gerald. 1916-1924 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Professional correspondence: Reid, W. B. 1895-1899 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Professional correspondence: Tichnor, Bryan W. 1887-1897 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Professional correspondence: "All the Young Lawyers." 1893-1920 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Letters requesting advice, information, etc.
    - Professional correspondence: Job requests. 1889-1924 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Professional correspondence: Letters of introduction and recommendation. 1889-1920 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Professional correspondence: Arizona Bar Association. 1902-1923 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Includes some material relating to city and county groups.
    - Professional correspondence: Arizona State Board of Law Examiners. 1912-1922 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Office correspondence chiefly between staff and Selim Franklin during summer vacations. 1891-1925 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
    - Legal correspondence. 1886-1927 (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
      Letters from clients and others regarding legal matters and various cases not identified elsewhere in the collection.
    - Biographical Sketch. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Combination of Safe." (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sale of Selim Franklin's bicycle. December 1888-January 1889 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Commission as Notary Public. 1887-1909 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - City license tax receipts to practice law. 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Personal income taxes. 1918-1922 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Recommended Lawyers" list. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Automobiles. 1917-1926 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Correspondence regarding repairs, shipping, insurance, license plates and bills for gasoline and services.
    - Autobiographical notes and personal compositions. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sessions Laws of the Legislative Assembly of the Territory of Arizona, 15th-19th Legislatures. 1889-1897 (Box 11)
      Selim Franklin's annotated copy.
    - Notebook (not fully identified). (Box 11)
      Contains notes by Selim Franklin regarding land grant cases, holographic Articles of Incorporation of the Arizona Silver Bell Mining Company (re-written to apply to the Bush-Swan Electric Light Company of Tucson); some financial records; and the "Record of A. M. Franklin, Notary Public," May 1886-1887.
    - Letter Books. 1884-1887 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Letter Books. January-June 1893 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Letter Books. June 1893-January 1894 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letter Books. November 1894-May 1895 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letter Books. 1895?-May 1896 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Letter Books. December 1897-August 1898 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letter Books. February-October 1901 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letter Books. January-September 1914 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letter Books. June 1917-December 1917 (Box 14)
    - Letter Books. December 1917-April 1918 (Box 14)
    - Letter Books. April 1918-November 1918 (Box 14)
    - Letter Books. November 1918-April 1919 (Box 15)
    - Letter Books. May 1919-November 1919 (Box 15)
    - Letter Books. December 1919-February 1921 (Box 15)
  - Case Files and Financial Records, 1883-1927
    - Record of Cases: #1-96. 1883-1889 (Box 16)
    - Record of Cases: #301-500. 1890-1899 (Box 16)
    - Record of Cases: #791-1099. 1902-1911 (Box 16)
    - Notes on legal cases and property. (Box 17, Volume 1-11)
    - Financial records: Cash Book and Ledger. 1883-1888 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Financial records: Cash Book. 1890-1892 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Financial records: Cash Books. August 1899-January 1922 (Box 18, Folder 3-6)
    - Financial records: Ledgers. 1896-1913 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Financial records: Arizona National Bank, Tucson, Arizona. 1894-1924 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Financial records: Miscellaneous banks and check stubs. 1893-1926 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Financial records: Bancroft-Whitney Co., law publisher. 1887-1904, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Financial records: Frank Shepard, law bookseller. 1887-1925 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Financial records: Lawyers' Co-operative Publishing Co. 1887-1925 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Financial records: West Publishing Co. 1886-1925 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Financial records: Miscellaneous books. 1887-1927 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Financial records: Subscriptions. 1887-1927 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Financial records: Cigars. 1888-1924 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Financial records: Personal purchases. 1888-1924 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Including jewelry, toys, sports equipment, wedding invitations, Christmas cards, also bills from Tucson drug stores, laundry and cleaning establishments.
    - Bills and correspondence for clothing: Lindsay Bros., Tailors, St. Louis. 1888-1890 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bills and correspondence for clothing: Bullock & Jones Co., Tailors, San Francisco. 1888-1905 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bills and correspondence for clothing: B. Altman & Co., New York. 1899-1927 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bills and correspondence for clothing: Mills & Hagbom, Tailors, San Francisco. 1906-1926 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bills and correspondence for clothing: Harry A. Drachman Shoe Co., Tucson, Arizona. 1921-1924 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bills and correspondence for food. 1891-1923 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Includes Tucson dairies and grocery stores.
    - Bills and correspondence for household furnishings. 1887-1924 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Bills and correspondence for plants, trees and seeds. 1898-1924 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Bills and correspondence for office supplies and furniture. 1888-1926 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Bills and correspondence: L. Zeckendorf and Co. 1895-1900 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Bills and correspondence from various retail merchants. 1911-1924 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Merchants include Albert Steinfeld & Co., W. F. Kitt's Sons, Rebeil Commercial Company and Montgomery Ward & Co.
  - Mining Case Files, 1880-1927
    - Fletcher, George N. of Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd., etc.: Correspondence. 1880-1895 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Fletcher, Charles R. of Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd., etc.: Correspondence. 1886-1927 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Mammoth-Collins Gold Mining Co., Ltd., & Mammoth Gold Mines, Ltd.: Correspondence. 1886-1894 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd.: Correspondence. 1895-1905 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd.: Legal papers, maps and notes. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Farmer's Loan & Trust Co. vs. Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd.: Letter Book of M. P. Freeman. October 1896-April 1898 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Mohawk Gold Mining Co.: Correspondence. 1894-1927 (Box 22, Folder 1-6)
    - Albert Steinfeld vs. Mohawk Gold Mining Co. 1898-1904 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - J.B. Brown vs. Mohawk Gold Mining Co. 1910-1911 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - City Bank of Hartford vs. Mohawk Gold Mining Co. 1927 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Mohawk Gold Mining Co.: Miscellaneous legal and insurance papers, maps, etc. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Correspondence. September 1899-September 1907, 1916-1918 (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Payrolls, legal papers, court cases (Charles E. Udall vs. Mammoth Cyanide Co., 1902-1903). (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Insurance receipts. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Letter Book. 1899-1902 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Two books of check stubs. April 1900-May 1902 (Box 23)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Checks from Consolidated National Bank, Tucson, Arizona. 1900-1902 (Box 23)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Payroll Warrants. 1901-1902 (Box 23)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: F. W. Braun & Co., Los Angeles, California. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Sunset Telephone & Telegraph Co., San Francisco, California. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: L. Zeckendorf & Co., Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: W. J. Corbett, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Levi Booth & Sons, Los Angeles, California. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Denver Fire Clay Co., Denver, Colorado. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Gardiner, Worthen & Goss Co., Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Oracle & Mammoth Stage Line, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Orndorff Hotel, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: F. J. Villaescua, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Manzo & Ochoa, Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Mountain View Hotel, Oracle, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co. Bills: Tucson Lumber Co., Tucson, Arizona. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Mammoth Cyanide Co.: Miscellaneous bills and receipts. 1899-1902 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence from various mining companies. 1896-1900 (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
      Mining companies include the Pima Mining & Smelting Co., Coyote Copper Co., and Helmet Peak Co.
    - Correspondence from various mining companies. 1898-1903 (Box 26, Folder 1-9)
      Mining companies include the Ray Copper Mines, Ltd., and Globe Minerals Exploration Co., Ltd.
    - Correspondence from various mining companies. 1904-1917 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      Mining companies include the Ray Copper Mines, Ltd., and Globe Minerals Exploration Co., Ltd., Atlas Copper Mines, and Red Rock Copper Co.
    - Ray Mines Co. vs. Peter A. Schilling. June 1902 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - C. M. Gordon & Ray Copper Mines vs. Tucson Street Railway. 1904-1906 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Patents for 17 mines and mill sites. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Atlas Copper Mines and Red Rock Copper Co. 1898-1918 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Ajo Mining and Development Co. 1883-1908 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Arizona-Apache Copper Mining and Smelting Co.: Legal cases involving Frank Foran and W. W. Reeves. 1907-1910 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: Articles of Incorporation, reports, legal papers, etc. 1905-1910 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: Correspondence, bills, etc. 1905-1923 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: Bankruptcy. 1911-1913 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: Various cases. 1911-1913 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: C. H. Wright cases. 1911-1920 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Arizona Gold Mines and Milling Co.: Miscellaneous papers. 1914-1922 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Four Metals Mining Co.: Correspondence. 1908-1912, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Four Metals Mining Co.: D. P. Pennywitt vs. S. F. Johnson. 1909-1910 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
    - Four Metals Mining Co. vs. S. F. Johnson. June 1909-December 1911 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Four Metals Mining Co.: Various cases. 1909-1910, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
      Cases involve:
      S. E. Hunger
      S. F. Johnson
      C. H. Gardner
      B. J. Mack
      Territory of Arizona
      C. McPherson
      P. R. Sullivan
      M. B. Trickey
      B. Maier & Co.
      G. D. Gross
      Washington Trading Co.
      A. J. Edwards
      Selim M. Franklin
    - United Arizona Copper Co. and the Reward Mines. February-October 1907 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Reward Consolidated Mining Co.: Legal papers. 1902-1913 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Reward Consolidated Mining Co.: Meetings of stockholders and directors, miscellaneous papers. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Reward Consolidated Mining Co.: Mine locations notices and deeds, etc. 1902-1907 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Reward and Virginia Mining Claims (Abstract of Title). (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Casa Grande-Arizona Copper Co. 1916-1924 (Box 30, Folder 6)